PHYSICIST OSVALDO ROSALES PÉREZ

Software and Blockchain Engineer, problem solver, continuous learner and passionate about building a decentralized future on top of Bitcoin and the Lightning Network 4.

CONTACT



📞 +52 6461164406 [Telegram 🕢]

Ensenada, B.C., México. UTC-07

@osvaldorosales96

Osvaldo Rosales

Osvaldo Rosales | Physics Stories

SKILLS

Languages

Spanish Native language English C2, Full professional proficiency French C1, Fluent

</> Programming Languages

Pvthon Bitcoin Script Javascript Solidity



Rust | Swift | C | Bash | SQL | React

🙈 Software Tools & Libraries Experience

Bitcoin & Lightning

BitcoinDevelopmentKit, python-bitcoinrpc, BitcoinJS, IbexHUB API.

Node Management

MyNode/RaspiBlitz, LNBits, RTL, Voltage.

Raspberry Pi, Arduino, Texas instrument Launchpad MSP430, 3D printing.

Ethereum & Polygon

Python Brownie Framework, Ganache, Remix, OpenZeppelin, Web3JS, Infura.

Web Backend

Django, Flask, NodeJS, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Data Analysis and Visualization (Python) Numpy, Pandas, SciPy, StatsModels, Matplotlib, Seaborn.

Machine Learning, AI & Data extranction OpenCV, Keras, TensorFlow, SciKit-Learn, Tesseract OCR Engine, Scrapy Web.

CI/CD

Docker and Docker Compose, AWS. lenkins

x² Highly proficient in mathematics

Probability and Statistics Advanced Calculus



Differential Equations Numerical Simulations



BITCOIN & PERSONAL PROJECTS

% - **Bitcoin-Lightning IOS Wallet** [<u>Link]</u>: Developed a prototype for a non-custodial, descriptor-based IOS Bitcoin wallet, implementing the BitcoinDevelopmentKit, connecting to my own Electrum server for Blockchain data and successful transaction broadcast on mainnet. Also added Lightning Payments functionality through the IBEXHub API Service.

6 - Chaotic Attraction [Link]: Developed a 3D interactive experience to touch and play with the **Butterfly Effect**. The numerical simulation runs in the browser, solving a Lorentz System of differential equations to get the next step for each particle. Every time you see it, the simulation is completely unique. Deployed on IPFS.

EXPERIENCE

02/2022 - Present

♥ CryptoMX, Tijuana, México

Blockchain Consultant (Remote)

- Assisted on the creation of online educational content and courses about Bitcoin, Ethereum Smart-Contracts and NFTs by communicating technical information, at different levels of complexity, e.g., Elliptic curve cryptography, Hashing algorithms, Proof of Work vs Proof of Stake consensus and smart-contract interactions.
- Developed Solidity smart-contracts for ERC-721 NFTs and Royalties Splitters, tested and deployed on Ethereum and Polygon networks with the Python Brownie Framework.

₩ 08/2021 - Present

Senior Platform Engineer (Remote) ♀ MedTrainer, Queretaro, México

- Lead the newly established Python Automation Team from initial proposal and architecture design to the final delivery of an Automation Microservices Platform for on-demand data retrieval and web scraping of several US-States medical professional licensing websites.
- Maintained constant communication and collaboration with the company CTO, DevOps and frontend departments about the projects design and implementation.
- Transformed each data validation task from 1 employee-hour to 1 automated-minute.
- Established standards for good practices in python microservices and test-driven development as well as standards for **Detailed Documentation and Templates** for future projects.

1 02/2021 - 08/2021

Arkus Nexus, Tijuana, México

Machine Learning Engineer (Remote)

- Developed Machine learning models for patter recognition and text extraction from images implementing Keras, OpenCV and Tesseract OCR Engine. This models were served through a Flask API and triggered as Celery asyncronous tasks on AWS with a RabbitMQ message broker.
- Supported other **Django** and **Flask** web projects within the company.

1 01/2019 - 02/2021

Grupo Molecular, Tijuana, México Lead Developer and Researcher

- Lead a team of developers on the design and delivery of a Financial Analysis Web Platform that fetched and analyzed real-time data from various APIs implementing Django REST Framework, PostgreSQL database, Celery asyncronous tasks on the backend and NodeJS+ReactJS on the frontend.
- Developed Machine learning models for time-series forecasting and pattern recognition implementing Long-Short Term Memory Models and Convolutional Neural Networks.
- Delivered statistical data analysis and visualization of experimental results in different research projects with Python tools.

EDUCATION

2014 - 2019

Universidad Autónoma de Baja California, Science Faculty, Ensenada, México.

Degree in Physics

2017 - 2018

Université Claude Bernard Lyon 1. Faculté des Sciences et Technologies, Lyon, France. **Academic Exchange**